# VLAD-EMIL FLORE

Senior Full Stack Engineer flore.vlad@gmail.com +4915208383107

#### PROFILE

I am a Software / Full Stack Engineer holding a **Bachelor** and a **Master** in **Computer Science** and being professionally active in this field since 2008. In my professional work, I focused mainly on **Web Development**, **Backend** as well as **Frontend**. In the last 7 years, I have been also working as a **Software Consultant**, offering implementation and consultancy services to different clients, most of them being in Germany.

I am **Oracle certified** - **OCA** and **OCP** for **Java 8** and I enjoy learning new things and taking on new endeavours. Part of my spare time I dedicate to broadening my knowledge and becoming better, the reason why I continuously attend various **MOOCs** - **Coursera**, Udemy, Edx, Udacity and I am being active on professional online learning platforms, like **JetBrains Academy** . When time allows it, I also attend and present at **technical conferences**.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Senior Technical Consultant, virtual 7 GmbH, Nürnberg

Lead Software Developer, IT-Systemhaus der Bundesagentur für Arbeit, Nürnberg

Full Stack Developer, Bundesamt für Migration und Flüchtlinge -BAMF, Nürnberg 2018 – 2019

Software Developer, IT-Systemhaus der Bundesagentur für Arbeit, Nürnberg 2014 – 2018

Software Developer, virtual 7 Romania S.R.L., Timişoara 2008 — 2014

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Informatics, West University of Timişoara, Timişoara

2008 - 2010

Artificial Intelligence and Distributed Computing

Grade: 9 of 10

Bachelor of Science in Informatics, West University of Timişoara, Timişoara

2004 - 2008

**Computer Science** 

Computer Architecture, Algorithms, Data Structures, Programming (C, C++, Java), Mathematical Bases of Computers, Algebra, Computational Logics, Formal Languages and Automata Theory, Mathematical Analysis, Compiling Techniques, Graph Theory and Combinatorics, Ordinary and Partial Differential Equations, Operating Systems, Databases, Geometry, Real and Complex Calculus, Logical and Functional Programming, Probability,

Unix Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Numerical Methods, Statistics, Neural Networks, Computer Networks, Operational Research, Modeling and Simulation, Image Processing, Web Technologies, Local Network Administration, Computer Graphics, Intelligent Systems, Parallel Computing, Security and Cryptography

Grade: 9.67 of 10 (ranked 7 of 95 graduates)

Ī	IN	IKS

Blog Linkedin

#### SKILLS

Java	Full Stack Development
Web Development	Angular
Computer Programming	Software Craftsmanship
Test Driven Development	Spring Framework
Spring Boot	RESTful WebServices
Git	GitHub
Leadership and Teamwork	DevOps
Docker	Ansible
JavaScript	HTML & CSS
Bootstrap	SQL
AWS Lambda	Kotlin
Python	
LANGHAGES	
LANGUAGES English	German
Romanian	

#### COURSES

Algorithms, Part I, Coursera (Princeton University)

JULY 2020 - PRESENT

#### **Core Spring Training, Pivotal**

MARCH 2020 - MARCH 2020

#### Software Design and Architecture Specialization, Coursera (University of Alberta)

NOVEMBER 2019 - JUNE 2020

#### Python for Everybody Specialization, Coursera (University of Michigan)

NOVEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

#### Version Control with Git, Coursera (Atlassian)

JULY 2019 - JULY 2019

#### CERTIFICATIONS

#### Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer, online

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2020

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/23a81167-a908-437d-aec4-87f739fdc9c3/linked in profile

#### Software Design and Architecture, online

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2020

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/3PYQED43WWYV

#### Python for Everybody, online

JANUARY 2020 - JANUARY 2020

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/TWKG5SP5EL2D

#### Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer, online

MAY 2019 - MAY 2019

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/446d4d47-4493-4426-a7ab-034fe8675273/linked in profile

#### REFERENCES

Catalina Hritcu (HR Business Partner) from virtual7 Romania S.R.L.

0040787539359

#### **HOBBIES**

Travelling, Reading, Learning, Swimming



# CERTIFICATE OF RECOGNITION



Vlad-Emil Flore

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer

THIS CERTIFIES THAT ABOVE NAMED IS
RECOGNIZED BY ORACLE CORPORATION AS AN
ORACLE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL

June 02, 2020

DATE

DAMIEN CAREY

SENIOR VICE PRESIDENT, ORACLE UNIVERSITY



4 Courses

Object-Oriented Design

**Design Patterns** 

Software Architecture

Service-Oriented Architecture



06/15/2020

## **Vlad-Emil Flore**

has successfully completed the online, non-credit Specialization

# Software Design and Architecture

The recipient of this certificate has completed the Software Design and Architecture Specialization. This achievement required mastering knowledge and demonstrating applications of design principles, patterns, and architectures to create reusable and flexible software applications and systems. The Capstone Project provided practical assessment of the acquired knowledge and skills through the continuous development and documentation of an Android application from a single user app that stores data locally to a multi-user app that stores data remotely.

Kenny Wong

Kenny Wong Associate Professor Computing Science, Faculty of Science

The online specialization named in this certificate may draw on material from courses taught on-campus, but the included courses are not equivalent to on-campus courses. Participation in this online specialization does not constitute enrollment at this university. This certificate does not confer a University grade, course credit or degree, and it does not verify the identity of the learner

Verify this certificate at: coursera.org/verify/specialization/3PYQED43WWYV



**5 Courses** 

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

**Python Data Structures** 

Using Python to Access Web Data

Using Databases with Python

Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python



01/11/2020

### **Vlad-Emil Flore**

has successfully completed the online, non-credit Specialization

## Python for Everybody

This Specialization builds on the success of the Python for Everybody course and will introduce fundamental programming concepts including data structures, networked application program interfaces, and databases, using the Python programming language. In the Capstone Project, you'll use the technologies learned throughout the Specialization to design and create your own applications for data retrieval, processing, and visualization.

Charles Severance
Clinical Associate
Professor, School of
Information
University of Michigan

The online specialization named in this certificate may draw on material from courses taught on-campus, but the included courses are not equivalent to on-campus courses. Participation in this online specialization does not constitute enrollment at this university. This certificate does not confer a University grade, course credit or degree, and it does not verify the identity of the learner.

virtual7 Romania S.R.L.
Piata Consiliul Europei, Nr. 2E
United Business Center 3, Timis
J35/3070/2004
RO 16876814
Timisoara, Romania
Tel: 004 0787 539 359

May 29<sup>th</sup>, 2020

To Whom It May Concern,

It is with great pleasure that I am writing this recommendation letter for Mr. Vlad Flore. I have known Mr. Vlad Flore on a professional level for two years now. During this time, I found him to be detail oriented and a solid and dependable professional. He would strive to understand the background and objectives regarding his assignments and ensure that they get done on time.

He is very proactive, approaches tasks with the right priority, does not need supervision but seeks help when needed. He communicates well and is very collaborative, he loves to learn and teach.

Mr. Vlad Flore has been working at virtual7 since 2008, when he joined the company as a young talent. Since then he has continued to grow and develop and has never stopped being curious and interested in everything that is new in the IT market, and now he's became a senior technical consultant very appreciated in his area of expertise.

Mr. Flore also held many presentations, internal and external, participated in trainings, internal and external and specialized in various fields, also obtaining several certifications. As external presentations I would like to mention that he held twice a conference, in 2015 and 2017 at DOAG (Deutsche Oracle-Anwendergruppe).

He worked on various projects, with different technologies, mainly with Java and Oracle WebCenter Content (Content Management System from Oracle).



virtual7 Romania S.R.L.
Piata Consiliul Europei, Nr. 2E
United Business Center 3, Timis
J35/3070/2004
RO 16876814
Timisoara, Romania
Tel: 004 0787 539 359

After 2014 Mr. Vlad Flore, started to work as a detachment in Germany which taught him to work in an international and multicultural environment.

In all these 11 years of collaboration in Romania, Mr. Vlad Flore proved to be a great colleague, a perfect professional, a person you could always rely on.

He has visited and worked with colleagues from different backgrounds in different countries and is very approachable. He is a natural problem solver. I highly recommend him and i believe that he will be a big asset to any team he works with. I wish him all the best.

Sincerely,

Catalina Hritcu

HR Business Partner

virtual7 Romania S.R.L.